NDEGE ALBERT MUNENE

Software Engineer

Email: albertndege2@gmail.com

Portfolio: https://ndegealbert.vercel.app/

GitHub: https://github.com/ndegealbert

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ndege-albert-136178155/

Twitter: https://twitter.com/home?lang=en

Phone number: 0727596412

I am a full stack developer who is strongest on frontend development, I have more than 4 years of experience as a software developer, my experience has allowed me to acquire solid knowledge in software Engineering.

Working with multiple teams has made me programming language agnostic, whichever language is used, I can quickly learn and practice the best development Practices. I find joy in learning new things every day and solving real problems.

As a person I am vibrant, energetic and passionate about what I do, I have been appreciated for being committed to the quality of product and for always wanting to know "why"

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer

IPay Africa

June 2021 – to date

- Improving various legacy services efficiency and stability by introducing multi-threading and asynchronous processing
- Development, testing and documentation of APIs.
- Research on new fit for future technologies and active implementation. Design and implementation of microservice architectures

• Implemented the company's payment gateway – A platform that processed various payments such as merchant, utility and card payments, utilized different payment gateway to archive this .ie Mpesa Api ,Cellulant Api , Pesalink Api, Visa/Muster card , Mvisa, Amex and UnionPay

Key achievement:

- Acquired experience working in a fintech industry
- Maintained maximum uninterrupted flow of business-critical

Software Engineer

Adalabs Africa

Jan 2021 - June 2021

- Worked as a remote software developer of Agri-tech Startup at Tanzania in developing and deploying Phemarket, a Market place for connecting farmers to Sell their Product
- Built innovative microservices (REST-API) using Php and Node.js
- Built a Single page interactive web application using React, redux and styled-component
- Worked closely with other developers, UX designers, and systems analysts to deliver the product

Key achievement:

• Maintained maximum uninterrupted flow of business-critical

Software Engineer

Smart-beaver innovation.

May 2020 – Feb 2021

- Engineered modern applications (Smart beaver innovation management system) with PHP (Laravel), JavaScript (React), MySQL, and No SQL.
- Built innovative microservices (REST-API).
- Supported multiple teams, empowering them to do more through code reviews, and automated code quality checks.

Key achievement: Maintained maximum uninterrupted flow of business-critical

Computer Technician

Jkuat industrial park

Assembling Taifa laptop/DLP Tablet and 2019 census tablets-

May 2019 - Sep 2019

- Assembling and Configuring Tablet for 2019 census
- Installing firewalls and Testing census Devices
- Setting up server for Census data

Key achievement: Identified and dealt with a significant process of Assembling Tablets and Laptops

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology

Jomo Kenyatta university of Agriculture and Technology

May 2016- Feb 2020

- Heavy focus on full stack engineering with modules on both front and backend processes.
- Built a mock payment system for an Android ecommerce app for a senior year project.
- Built Learning projects which can be found on my portfolio/GitHub

Skills:

Programming languages

- JavaScript (ES6) /TypeScript
- Php
- Java
- Go lang currently learning

Databases:

- MySQL
- PostgreSQL
- Mongo DB

Libraries and framework:

- React.js & React-native
- Next.js
- Redux
- Laravel
- Spring-boot

Design and prototyping tool:

Figma

Certification:

• AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner – On progress

References

Gorge Nduati Mwangi

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

Lecturer

0722610473

nduatigm@gmail.com

Tools & platform:

- Git & GitHub
- Docker
- Webpack
- Netlify
- Linux

Cloud Platform:

Amazon Web Service

EC2, RDS, IAM, S3, DynamoDB

Fred Ochieng

Jkuat industrial Park

Supervisor

0728289834

fredochiengokeyo@gmail.com